<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tyler Koske]]></title>
  <link href="http://numo16.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://numo16.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-12T23:50:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://numo16.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tyler Koske]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[numo16@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New (and First) Book Potentially in the Works]]></title>
    <link href="http://numo16.github.io/blog/2013/06/19/new-and-first-book-potentially-in-the-works/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T21:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://numo16.github.io/blog/2013/06/19/new-and-first-book-potentially-in-the-works</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You read that right, I may be writing a book. A major publisher of books for the tech crowd has approached me to ask if I would be interested in authoring a short book on programming using specific technologies (more info as I find out what exactly I am allowed to say). Needless to say, I am excited for the opportunity and a bit terrified, as I haven’t really done a large writing project in a long time…Especially not one that will be published through a major publisher.</p>

<p>All that being said, I am very excited about the prospect and I intend on chronicling my experiences during the process here, as I am able. This should be a fun and exciting challenge. Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress...]]></title>
    <link href="http://numo16.github.io/blog/2010/10/25/progress/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-25T21:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://numo16.github.io/blog/2010/10/25/progress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Between classes, work, and figuring out everything for Imagine Cup 2011, I’ve been busy as hell.  Next week is my last week for both my Game Scripting and Data Structures and Algorithms class, which both take up a considerable amount of my available free time.  At work I’ve been wrapping up a market share study and implementing a few long awaited features for one of our main apps.  So, after those two, that has left me a few hours to deliberate over which theme to pick for Imagine Cup, figure out team members, and figure out the direction and concept of the game.  Between Zander and myself, with a nice random idea from Jarrod, I think we’ve nailed down exactly what we want to do for the competition.  Zander has decided he definitely wants in on this, so it is up to me at this point to decide if I’ll be able to spare the time to make this work, which I have pretty much decided that I will. In the meantime, I’ve decided to setup the project environment, complete with subversion repos, integration and build server, wiki, issue tracker, and a bunch of other things.  <!-- more -->Everything is setup and hosted on my server like so:</p>

<h2>Subversion: <a href="http://www.open.collab.net/products/subversion/">Collabnet Subversion Edge</a></h2>

<p>OK, so this setup is pretty awesome.  CSVN is a simple installable package, sporting a subversion server and a nice web management interface.  It can integrate with a few bug trackers and has nice connectivity with Visual Studio, thanks to their Ankh SVN plugin.  The best part, it’s free!</p>

<h2>CI and Build Server: <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/">Jetbrains TeamCity</a></h2>

<p>TeamCity is a pretty awesome setup.  It’s a free continuous integration and build server that will automatically build my projects whenever a new version is committed to the main repo.  This also has a great web management interface, allowing me to monitor builds, setup build scripts for projects, and also integrates with a few well known issue trackers.</p>

<h2>Wiki, Issue Tracker, etc…: <a href="http://info.tiki.org/tiki-index.php">TikiWiki</a></h2>

<p>I needed somewhere to have a central collaboration area, to keep all of our ideas and the project documented.  I thought about using media wiki at first, but after my first initial experience with dealing with that mess, I decided to seek out better alternatives.  TikiWiki seemed to fit the bill with its wiki, forum, issue tracker, and a bunch of other features I won’t end up using.  It’s pretty awesome.  The only problem I can foresee with it for this project currently, is that CSVN and TeamCity do not integrate with the issue tracker in TikiWiki, which means I may have to setup Bugzilla or something later.</p>

<p>Setting up the environment like this is a new thing to me, but after reading through several topics on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">StackOverflow</a>, it seemed like a good idea to setup the environment like this just to make everything a bit easier and a more automated, streamlined process.  I’m still working out the kinks, so time will tell if all of this will be a help or hindrance.  Next item on the docket, a better backup system…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's about time...]]></title>
    <link href="http://numo16.github.io/blog/2010/10/21/its-about-time/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-21T21:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://numo16.github.io/blog/2010/10/21/its-about-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So after putting off starting this blog for quite a while now, I’ve decided it is time to do this. I guess the main reason I never really did anything with it before was lack of motivation. I kept asking myself what I would write about or why should I take time out of my increasingly busy schedule to write a bit of drivel, here and there. Well, I’ve been pushing myself into game programming a bit more lately after taking an XNA class and loving it, and decided it’s time I start chronicling my progress and interesting things I run across.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Lately, I’ve been reading a lot of the stuff over on <a href="http://gamedev.stackexchange.com/">Game Development Stack Exchange</a> in order to figure out where to start when it comes to game development in C++.  I’ll start out by saying, I haven’t used C++ in a long time, as I’ve been developing in PHP at work and my latest programming classes have been C# and VB.Net.  So, a refresher was in order, along with figuring out where to start.  So, I found SDL and started tearing through some game dev specific tutorials and I must say, C++ is coming back to me pretty well.  In addition to the SDL tutorials, I’ve been watching the C++ videos over on <a href="http://www.3dbuzz.com/">3D Buzz</a>, which have also been an immense help in refreshing my knowledge of the language, as well as, helping me to figure out the overall structure of putting a game together from scratch. So far, everything has been great with refreshing and learning.</p>

<p>Although learning C++ game dev has been great and a nice challenge, so far, I may find myself jumping back into XNA for a while.  I got a newsletter yesterday reminding me about the <a href="http://www.imaginecup.us/">Imagine Cup 2011</a> competition that Microsoft is putting on.  I took a look through the game design category and decided it looked like something doable, if I were able to get the right group of creative minds together for my team.  I read through the theme and came up with a couple decent ideas right away that I will play around with a bit.  After some mind-mapping and discussion with my probable team members last night, I have a few better ideas that just may work out.  Stay tuned…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
